How do you use a telephone is something I get asked everyday.
My name is Kathy Pabst Robshaw, Telephone Effectiveness and I teach people how to use a telephone.
The first thing you need to be aware of is that telephone has got numbers on it, from 1- 0 on the, on the telephone pad.
If it's a local number, you just need to dial the seven digits, without the area code.
If it's a long distance number, you have to put 1 in front of the number to reach a long distance number and the call goes to without even thinking about it.
So keep track of the phone number that you have to call regularly and as long as your phone actually has a memory you can actually save those telephone numbers.
When you're dialing, when you're talking on the phone, don't shout, speak in a normal voice.
If someone can't hear you, it might be better to suggest that you call them back instead of, if they can't hear what you're saying instead of shouting 'cause it disturbs other people around you as well.
The other feature that we have with the telephone nowadays is call waiting.
Calls can come into you while you're on one phone, another call comes in.
Simply put that call on hold, tell the person first I have to put you on hold for a second, take the call that comes in, then put that call on hold go back to your original phone call.
The call waiting is another good way to take advantage of the telephone, to do two calls at the same time.
So don't yell, know the number that you're going to call. Know if it's national that you have to dial 1 before the telephone number and speaks softly, speaks clearly; Kathy Pabst Robshaw, Telephone Effectiveness.